all right
[Music]
cancer prevalence is predicted to
continue to increase but the good news
is that between 30 and 50 percent of
most common cancers might be preventable
through diet and lifestyle changes take
breast cancer for example the most
common female internal cancer diagnosis
in the United States and the second
thing cause of female cancer death after
lung cancer
but there's a growing body of evidence
that breast cancer incidents can be
reduced with an overall healthy
lifestyle which includes a high quality
diet consisting of fruits vegetables
whole grains and legumes like beans flu
peas chickpeas and lentils greater
adherence to a more Mediterranean style
diet was associated with a lower risk of
cancer mortality including less breast
cancer
and an analysis of the individual
components of the Mediterranean diet
revealed that the protective effects
appear to be most attributable to eating
more fruits vegetables and whole grains
contributing to mounting evidence that a
plant-based diet is the most beneficial
dietary pattern for breast cancer
survivors wait the same diet that can
help you prevent cancer can also help
you survive cancer that's one of the 10
recommendations from the prestigious
American Institute for cancer research
after a cancer diagnosis followed the
same recommendations to maintain a
healthy weight exercise either diet rich
in four things whole grains vegetables
fruits and beans but limit fast food and
processed junk and limit consumption of
meats soda and alcohol
okay but does adherence to these
guidelines actually translate into less
cancer
yes substantially reduce the risk of
total cancer providing robust evidence
that the guidelines for cancer
prevention should be widely disseminated
in society about half the folks were
failing in the healthy weight and
physical activity departments but more
than 90 percent were failing on eating
enough plant Foods or limiting enough
meat and processed junk but I guess the
glass 10 full interpretation is that
given that many people do not meet the
recommendations there's a great
potential for cancer prevention
specific to breast cancer risk women who
met most of those recommendations only
had half the breast cancer risk compared
to women who only nailed a couple if you
could only do one of those
recommendations the limiting animal food
seemed most protective adherence to the
recommendations was also associated with
higher survival in cancer patients who
already had cancer this was also true
for older female cancer survivors most
of whom were suffering from breast
cancer
a good proxy for Whole Food plant intake
is dietary fiber since it's not found in
animal foods and is depleted or
completely absent in processed foods and
higher dietary fiber consumption was
associated with a 37 lower risk of dying
from all causes put together and 28
percent lower risk of dying specifically
from breast cancer among breast cancer
survivors and it didn't take much there
was like a 10 drop in death risk for
every 5 grams a day increment in dietary
fiber intake that's just like a cup of
oatmeal or broccoli or a third a cup of
beans a cancer diagnosis May provide a
teachable moment for cancer survivors to
make positive changes in their health
behaviors
even more importantly higher fiber
intake may help prevent breast cancer in
the first place yes fiber could help
directly by feeding your good gut floor
which then produce anti-inflammatory
compounds or could just be an indicator
of total whole plant food intake
adherence to the cancer prevention
recommendations isn't just associated
with higher survival in cancer patients
and lower risk of dying from cancer but
lower risk of dying overall that's the
beauty of eating a more plant-based diet
the same diet that's anti-cancer is also
anti-heart disease and even apparently
anti-lung disease
conclusion results of the study suggest
following the cancer prevention diet and
lifestyle recommendations could
significantly increase longevity
[Music]